### Rubén Herrero Rabadán

Date of birth: 22/03/1990 Phone number: 616 045 808 E-Mail: rh.miracles@gmail.com https://github.com/herrecito

#### About me

I have experience as a programmer in several areas, from low level microcontroller programming to interface design, with web development being my area of expertise.

Inside web development, I know the full application life cycle, and I am equally confortable as a back-end or front-end developer, even though I have more work experience as a front-end developer.

I have been a team leader, participating in functional analysis meetings, planning and organizing tasks, providing technical support to other teams, and helping in personnel selection processes.

I enjoy learning and sharing knowledge. I strongly believe in learning from first principles, and I am interested not just in the latest technologies, but also in best practices and how they apply to the development process.

## Work experience

**SOFTWARE ENGINEER, TIERRA AUDIO – 2019-2021** 

Functional analysis, back-end (Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL) and front-end (React, Redux) programming and unit testing (Mocha, Chai, Sinon) of an internal business support platform.

Functional analysis, back-end (Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL) and front-end (Vue with SSR, Vuex) programming and unit testing (Mocha, Chai, Sinon) of the private customer area platform.

Infrastructure management and configuration of both platforms on Microsoft Azure, using the Infrastructure as Code (IaC) approach, with Pulumi and Ansible.

Development of an internal tool use to measure audio parameters, with C++, OpenGL and digital signal processing techniques.

Firmware programming for Espressif ESP32 microcontroller (C, C++, FreeRTOS, CMake).

#### WEB DEVELOPER, OKN-LEARNING - 2017-2019

Front-end developer, carrying out maintenance and development tasks on an LMS platform with over then years of history.

Subsequently, front-end team leader, tasked with the rebuilding of said platform using modern practices (TDD, CI).

WEB DEVELOPER, NEMÓTICA CONSULTORÍA - 2015-2017

Functional analysis, back-end (ASP.NET MVC, SQL Server) and front-end (ES6, Vue) programming, on a Single Page Application with real-time functionality (WebSockets).

## Education

GRADO EN INGENIERÍA AERONÁUTICA, UPM 2013-2015

DESARROLLADOR DE SITIOS WEB DINÁMICOS, MICROFORUM - 575H, 2015

# Further knowledge

- Languages: Native Spanish and fluid English (CAE C1 certificate).
- Linux, Windows and macOS operative systems.
- Acquainted with version control software (Git, GitHub).
- Agile methodologies (SCRUM).